contact@erichayesjohnson.com linkedin.com/in/eric-h-johnson

Eric Johnson

Experienced front-end developer with a track record at the world's most visited job site. Driven by a passion for UX, data visualization, and test automation. A self-motivated learner with a diverse background across various industries.

EXPERIENCE

UX Developer L2 — Indeed.com — (USA, Remote)

JAN 2023 - PRESENT

- Spearheaded the design and implementation of product features and A/B experiments
- Mentored team members in front-end best practices and company design system standards
- Conducted comprehensive code reviews with swift turnaround times, fostering quality and efficiency
- Assessed and evaluated interview take-home exercises, contributing to the hiring goals

UX Developer L1 — Indeed.com — (Tokyo, Japan/ USA, Remote)

APR 2021 - JAN 2023

- Developed diverse product features for job post automation and recommendations
- Fostered collaboration with UX Design and Research teams to effectively guide product direction
- Created comprehensive end-to-end prototypes to introduce new product flows to stakeholders
- Conducted an in-depth audit of third-party animation libraries to facilitate accelerated development

QA Automation Engineer L2 — Indeed.com — (Tokyo, Japan)

APR 2018 - APR 2021

- Played a vital role in building and upkeeping the internal automation framework
- Took charge of technical interview rounds, assessing and selecting top talent
- Pioneered the adoption of cutting-edge tooling and frameworks, enhancing efficiency and performance
- Mentored junior automation engineers and software engineers in automation best practices

QA Engineer — Indeed.com — (Tokyo, Japan)

AUG 2016 - APR 2018

- Developed comprehensive, full-stack automation test suites ensuring safe release cycles
- Performed thorough manual feature and end-to-end testing, identifying and documenting defects
- Orchestrated feature bug bashes, fostering collaboration among cross-functional teams
- Supervised CI/CD release management, guaranteeing smooth and timely product deployments

SKILLS

Languages/ Libs: JavaScript, TypeScript, React, Redux, CSS, GraphQL, Python

Tools: Figma, Storybook, Git, Gitlab, Jenkins, MySQL, terminal

Testing: Jest, React testing library, MSW, Selenium, Cypress, TestCafe

EDUCATION

Berklee College of Music

Bachelors of Arts - Music Production Engineering

2003 - 2007